A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Films FA753
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Films
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University.
FA753
1 Film Reels Actual extent unknown.
Scope and Contents
Contains films and video.
Conditions Governing Access
All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 48 business hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may require creation of an access surrogate. Applicable charges will apply.
Rockefeller University.; Rockefeller University.
- Rockefeller University Films, 1
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains films originating from Rockefeller University records, as well as various laboratories and the papers of select faculty.
  - 1972 Nobel Prize in Chemistry (Reel AV 705)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
    Scope and Contents note
    Film of a meeting between Christian B. Anfinsen (National Institute of Health), Stanford Moore (Rockefeller University), and William H. Stein (Rockefeller University).
    File Plan
    I 450 M786 Fe 1
  - Biochemistry of Heredity, c. 1958-1960 (Reel AV 729)
    Episode of NBC series Continental Classroom
    I 450 T189 Fe 2
  - Christmas Lecture 1965/1966: Dr. Allfrey (Reel AV 674)
    I 450 M679 Fb 3
  - Christmas Lecture 1965/1966: Dr. Mirsky (Reel AV 675)
    I 450 M679 Fb 4
  - Christmas Lecture 1965/1966: Dr. Mirsky, Dr. Allfrey, Dr. Coldrum (Reel AV 676)
    I 450 M679 Fb 5
  - Christmas Lecture 1965/1966: Nuclear Isolation (Reel AV 672)
    Recording of lecture by Dr. Mirsky on nuclear isolation, autolytic enzymes, red cells, and related experiments.
    I 450 M679 Fb 1
  - Dr. Lyman C. Craig (Reel AV 731)
    Episode of NBC series Continental Classroom with Dr. Lyman
    I 450 C844 Fe 1
  - Dr. Lyman C. Craig Films
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #1 (Reel AV 629)
      Conditions Governing Access
      I 450 C844 Fa 1
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #2 (Cells Color) (Reel AV 630)
      I 450 C844 Fa 2
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #3 (Reel AV 631)
      I 450 C844 Fa 3
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #4 (Reel AV 632)
      I 450 C844 Fa 362
    - Homologous Response (Some Original Positive of Salamander & Frog) (Reel AV 633)
      I 450 C844 Fa 4
    - [Untitled] (Reel AV 634)
      I 450 W436 Fa 363
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #5 (Reel AV 668)
      I 450 C844 Fb 1
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #6 (Reel AV 669)
      I 450 C844 Fb 2
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #7: "Countercurrent" (Reel AV 670)
      I 450 C844 Fb 3
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #8: "Countercurrent" (Reel AV 670A)
    - Dr. Craig Lyman #9 (Reel AV 671)
      I 450 C844 Fb 4
    - Dr. Craig C. Lyman (Reel AV 731)
  - DNA Extraction (Reel AV 673)
    Part of lecture by Dr. Mirsky on DNA centrifuge.
    I 450 M679 Fb 2
  - Experimental Epidemiology: An Investigation of the Causes Which Determine the Prevalence of Epidemic Diseases (Reel AV 724)
    An investigation of the causes which determine the prevalence of epidemic diseases, from Rockefeller University faculty member Leslie T. Webster.
    I 450 W395 Fe 1
  - The Future of Medicine, 1966 May (Reel AV 728)
    NBC television program from 1966 May about molecular biology, nucleic acids, and the new Merck Building.
    I 450 T189 Fe 1
  - Principles of Genetics Lecture Series
    - Genetic Loads in Mendelian Populations #25 (Reel AV 789)
      Lecture by Dr. T. Dobzhansky, Columbia University (#25 in series)
    - Mutegen-Induced Gene Mutation #23 (Reel AV 787)
      Lecture by Dr. H. J. Muller, Indiana University (#23 in series)
    - The Origin of Species, #28 (Reel AV 770)
      Lecture by Dr. G. L. Stebbins, University of California (#28 in series)
    - Selection, Genetic Death, and Genetic Radiation Damage. #26 (Reel AV 769)
      Lecture by Dr. T. Dobzhansky, Columbia University (#26 in series)
    - Virus Genetics: Bacteriophage #46 (Reel AV 774)
      Lecture by Dr. J. Lederberg, Stanford University (#46 in series)
    - Virus Genetics: Plant and Animal Viruses #47 (Reel AV 776)
      Lecture by Dr. J. Lederberg, Stanford University (#47 in series)
  - Profile of Dr. Dubos, 1970 (Reel AV 736)
    From WABC-TV with reporter Melba Tolliver visiting Dr. Rene Dubos in his RU laboratory and office. Discusses high school and local history, walk through neighborhood with wife Jean Dubos.
    I 450 D851
  - Reminiscences of Early Days of the Medical School, 1932 (Reel AV 834)
    Interview with Dr. William Welch about John Hopkins University
    I 216.3 Fe 1
  - Rene Dubos' Provocative New York, 1969 (Reel AV 737)
    Interview of Dr. Rene Dubos by reporter Earl Ubel (WCBS-TV) at RU campus. Discusses destruction of the environment, mismanagement of urban life, deterioration of the city, child development, effects of pollution on children, and the East River Drive waterfront.